[JEAN] I'll have 'em
set me up with some
prime real estate
in the interior.
[JEAN]
All day and night.
I'll sit and sip on the
finest liquor money can buy.
[JEAN] I won't care
what anyone says about it.
[JEAN]
After what I've gone through.
My wife and kids,
and their kids
deserve to live the good life.
[Knocking]
Jean, it's me.
[HANGE]
I'll be waiting outside.
[JEAN] You didn't really
notice anything.
There was nobody at the window.
Don't go. Don't think about it.
Just stay put.
Your place in the interior
is waiting. You've earned it.
[JEAN]
Stay right here.
[HANGE]
Hey, Jean. Good to see you.
Mikasa filled me in
on the situation.
I'm sorry I wasn't
there to help,
but considering
the circumstances,
you both did well.
Good work.
[HANGE] Levi's alive,
but he's in pretty dire shape.
He won't be fighting
anytime soon.
Listen. We made contact
with some Marleyan stragglers
and we've got the Cart Titan
on our side now.
We're going to try to stop Eren.
Killing everyone
isn't the answer.
What do you think
you can do to stop him?
[HANGE] First off,
we have to find more allies.
Our ultimate strategy
will depend on
who we have to work with,
but I doubt we'll be
able to accomplish
anything without
at least you guys,
plus a few more of the Nine.
It's safe to say our military
is effectively dissolved.
I'm not anybody's superior,
and I can't give you orders.
I can only ask you
for help and--
[MIKASA]
I'll do it.
Eren's killed too many already.
I won't sit back and
watch him steal more lives.
I know he's doing what
he believes he has to do
to protect us and the island,
but I can't let him
go through with it.
[HANGE]
Mikasa.
[JEAN] Think. Let's say we
figure out a way to stop Eren.
What comes after that?
[JEAN] Assuming he lives,
he's got the power
of the Founder
for four more years.
What do we do once he's gone?
We're still monsters
in the eyes of the world,
and after this, they'll only
be more terrified of us.
If we stop Eren now,
we're guaranteeing the
destruction of this island.
[HANGE]
Here's how I see it.
Marley will presume
that even if they
hit us with another
surprise attack,
we can respond
with the rumbling,
and that threat will be enough
to keep them off our backs
for the time being.
"If we don't exterminate
the island devils now,
it's only a matter
of time before
they come here
and destroy us all."
You remember
Willy Tybur's speech.
What's the world gonna do
when we prove him right?
[HANGE]
Nothing good, I know.
But at the very least,
this buys us a bit more time
to try to figure out
a better way.
Better way? We've spent years
looking for a better way
and this is where
it's gotten us!
We did our best and now
we've run out of time!
That's the reason
Eren decided to--
[HANGE]
What he's doing is wrong!
It's genocide, and I'll
be damned if I'm gonna
sit here and listen to you
try to justify it!
[HANGE]
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have
raised my voice.
Honestly, I don't think you're
wrong about what you said, Jean.
It was my hollow idealism
that drove Eren to do this.
What's more, before he
brought down the walls,
I wanted nothing more
than to run away.
I was gonna give up the fight
and cling to life at all costs,
but I couldn't,
because I'm still Commander
of the Survey Corps.
I can feel the eyes of our
fallen comrades watching me.
Everyone who gave their hearts
and souls to set humanity free.
Most of them died
too soon to learn that
past our walls,
humankind lived on.
But if they'd known,
would they want to
set our island free and
let the rest of the world burn?
Can you imagine any of them
being that selfish?
We'll only get one chance
to stop the slaughter.
And this is it.
[Gasps]
[JEAN] Hange. In the end,
I'll always be a Scout.
So is anybody gonna
help me out with these potatoes?
Or we just gonna
glare at each other?
[MAGATH]
We've gone from trading blows
to breaking bread
inside of a day, huh?
Out of curiosity, what made
you change your minds?
If you let Eren Jaeger succeed,
you'll be getting far more than
you ever could have hoped for.
You island devils will have
the world to yourselves.
We were the ones
trying to save it.
We would have been able to keep
Eren and Zeke
from coming into contact
if you hadn't stepped in at
the last second and helped them.
[HANGE] I'm only repeating what
I already told you, General,
but nobody here wants to be
an accessory to genocide.
That's why we're all hiding out
in the woods eating stew
instead of celebrating in town.
[MAGATH] So you finally figured
out who the good guys are, huh?
Are you kidding me?
You seriously think you're
in the right? You're crazy.
You people spent years
trying to murder us all,
and we're the bad guys 'cause
we didn't roll over and die?
Screw that! We learned to
fight like hell because
the only other option we had was
to let your Titans
eat us all alive!
We found a way to survive,
and now you're gonna
call us devils for it?
That's right.
You're exactly what we
always thought you were.
We let you fester
for too long on Paradis.
The world's about to
pay for that mistake.
You finally won your freedom,
and we can all see
what you're doing with it.
What'd I miss?
[JEAN] Plenty. Not a word
about your shock troops
destroying Eren's home
and making him
watch his mother
get eaten alive!
That's what started this!
If you wanna know
why this is happening,
go look in a mirror!
Right. Everything was fine
'til your buddy lost his mom.
I guess all those centuries
of Marley's people
getting ground under
Eldia's heel don't count
for anything in your mind.
[JEAN] Now you're gonna
play the victim over
something that happened
two thousand years ago?
[MAGATH]
It's like talking to a child.
It started two
thousand years ago.
Compared to the sum
of the carnage
and misery wrought by Eldia,
your island's suffering
is a joke.
[JEAN]
Excuse me?
[HANGE]
Okay. That's enough.
If we're gonna be
at each other's throats,
let's stick to
arguing about stuff
we lived through ourselves.
Look, Jean.
Our friend the general is
having a hard time understanding
why we're not acting like
the devils we are.
Giving up our paradise
to save a world
that wants us dead?
What devil in their right mind
would do a ridiculous
thing like that?
Have we gone mad?
What he doesn't know
is we Scouts spent a few months
living in that world,
so we can never go back to being
the ignorant island
devils we were.
[ANNIE]
Tell me,
can you honestly
bring yourself to kill him?
Are you truly ready
to kill Eren?
I don't think that's
our only option.
We can find another way.
[ANNIE] Exactly what
I expected you to say.
So what, you're gonna
try and persuade him?
He made the choice
to slaughter every man,
woman, and child on the planet.
You think you can
talk him back from that?
Well, I'm not assuming we can,
but we're never gonna know
for sure unless we try.
[ANNIE]
Sure. And say you fail.
You make your case and he still
refuses to stop the rumbling.
What's next?
It's him or the world.
Can you all see him
as your enemy?
That's what I thought.
We're the ones fighting to
protect our homeland now,
and we're going to do
what we need to do.
But if we have to
kill Eren to save Marley,
you're going to turn on us
to try to save your friend
and you know it.
[ANNIE]
Don't you, Mikasa?
Tell me I'm wrong.
You can't do it, right?
You care about
nothing more than him.
Can you imagine
turning against him?
If you want me out of the way,
then just come out and say it.
[Gasps]
Leonhart!
[ANNIE ] I know exactly
how you feel, Mikasa.
I'm not fighting Eren because
I think the world's
worth saving.
I'm doing it because
my dad's in Marley
and I don't want him to die,
but I can't save him
without your help.
If you really can change Eren's
mind, that's fine with me.
But until you get the chance,
we shouldn't be fighting.
[MIKASA]
Okay.
[Clanking]
[HANGE] Glad you worked
that out! And look!
Our stew's good
to go now. Dig in!
[HANGE]
Even with the horses rested,
we've got a five-hour
ride to the port.
From what Kiyomi told me,
the Azumabito have
a flying boat in the harbor,
and they'd been
planning to take off
and observe the rumbling
from the air.
We can use that to get close
to the Founding Titan.
[MAGATH]
I knew it.
The Azumabito were
helping you behind the scenes.
[HANGE] The problem is, we have
to find the Founder first,
and we won't have enough fuel
to fly around looking for him.
[MAGATH] Right, which is why
we captured this one.
Now, where is
Jaeger going first?
[YELENA]
I don't know.
And if I did, what reason
would I have to tell you?
[MAGATH] He learned about
the mainland from you.
You gave him the knowledge
to plan this attack.
He's going to be
picking his targets
based on what you taught him.
You should at least
be able to make a guess.
[YELENA]
Kiss my ass.
[MAGATH]
Hm?
What makes you think
I'll reverse course now
and help you Marleyan swine save
your godforsaken
hellhole of a country?
How about the fact
that it's your
only chance of
seeing another sunrise?
That won't work,
she doesn't wanna live.
But I thought you
started the Volunteers
'cause you wanted to liberate
your homeland from Marley.
Are ya gonna let
your country get flattened
just to spite the
"Marleyan Swine"?
It's a fair question.
[MAGATH] The answer's "yes."
Wanna know why?
Because she's a purebred
Marleyan pig, herself.
[PIECK TITAN]
You really caught us off guard
with the Liberio raid, Yelena.
But we got a bigger surprise
when we looked into your past.
You were born and raised
in a typical Marleyan family,
but you wrote yourself a new
life story when you met Zeke.
One where you were from
an annexed territory.
As you grew disillusioned
with Marley,
the story got more elaborate.
It evolved into
a grand fantasy about
saving the world with
your prince, and in time,
you hoped your fairy tale would
find its way into
the history books.
Your commitment to the lie
is honestly impressive.
[YELENA] "Save the world."
Those might be the sweetest,
most alluring words
a person could hear,
don't you think?
[YELENA] Who wouldn't
want to imagine themselves
as the savior of hundreds of
millions of innocent lives?
To wash the bitterness of
hatred out of their mouths
with the honeyed taste
of righteousness?
From where I sit,
it looks like that's exactly
what all of you are
doing right now.
Seems to me you need to
have your memories jogged.
[YELENA]
Reiner Braun.
You were the one who breached
Shiganshina's inner gate.
Do you know how many
Eldians were devoured
by Pure Titans because of that?
[YELENA]
And Annie Leonhart.
I hear you killed
more than a few
Survey Corps members
in your time,
and that's before we
get into all the innocents
you trampled trying to fight
your way out of Stohess.
[YELENA] But let's not forget
the brave liberators of Paradis.
[YELENA] There's Armin,
the levelheaded one,
who seems far too kind to
cause the sort of bloodbath
he did at that harbor in Marley.
How high do you think
you could stack those corpses?
Don't forget the civilians.
There were plenty.
[YELENA] Not to sell
the rest of you short.
Everyone gave a heroic
performance in Liberio.
Jean, most of all.
Little Falco here threw himself
in front of you
to protect the Cart,
but you didn't
let that stop you from
firing your thunder spear,
did you?
And of course.
You thought you'd all
made it out clean
until Gabi gunned down Sasha.
What a sweetheart that girl was.
Even I couldn't help
but feel sad for her.
[YELENA]
And to you, she was family!
You went through
training together.
Went through hell together!
Losing her must have been more
painful than I could imagine.
This stew's pretty good, Hange.
Got enough for seconds?
Oh, we've got more than enough,
so don't be shy.
I wanna thank you
for this, Yelena.
You're baiting us into
airing out our grudges
so we can get it
out of our systems
and get our heads
on straight, right?
You'd have had someone
to vent to yourself,
if you hadn't blown
all your friends' brains out
to keep your fantasy alive.
Now you've got
nothing but a head
full of cutting remarks
and a death wish.
Ahh. So this is actually
pretty selfless of you.
[YELENA]
Right. Almost forgot.
You had mentioned another name.
He was already dead
by the time we met,
but I remember you said
you were good friends.
What was it? Marco.
As I recall.
You told me Annie had something
to do with his death,
didn't you?
Did you ever ask her
for details?
I bet she'll tell you.
I stole his ODM gear
and left him where the Titans
could get to him.
Marco got eaten because of me--
Annie was only following
the orders I was giving her.
[REINER]
During the fight in Trost,
Marco overheard me and Bertholdt
discussing something secret.
If we'd let him go,
he could've exposed us,
so we decided
we had to silence him.
We figured nobody
would think twice
about a Scout getting
eaten by a Titan.
So I tackled him onto a roof
and I pinned him down,
and I ordered Annie
to strip off his ODM gear.
Then. We just left him there.
Marco was stranded on
that rooftop without a rig,
and a Titan got to him.
So did he--
Did he say anything
before he was killed?
[REINER] He asked why I wasn't
willing to talk to him.
[JEAN] I think that
question still applies.
We haven't been willing to talk.
We all just started fighting
and assumed it had
to be to the death.
[HANGE]
But we can still change that.
A little while ago, we were
all ready to kill each other,
and now, here we are, talking.
It's something, right?
To think we'd all be
sitting around a campfire
sharing a meal with people
we once called enemies.
I stood and watched the Titan
as it devoured Marco,
and then a switch flipped,
and I couldn't figure out
why it was happening.
Huh?
[REINER]
I just snapped.
I flew into a rage,
hellbent on avenging Marco.
I cut down the Titan myself.
We get it, Reiner.
You're saying the guilt
of carrying out your mission
screwed with your head.
[REINER] Don't forgive me.
I'm truly worthless.
[JEAN]
I said we get it.
[REINER]
I'm sorry.
[JEAN grunting]
--[CONNY] Hey! Jean!
--[ARMIN] Get off him!
[JEAN grunting]
[CONNY]
Easy, man!
[ARMIN]
Stop!
[Yells]
[ALL gasp]
[FALCO]
Gabi!
[GABI]
I'm sorry.
We came here to kill
everyone on Paradis.
We wanted to stage
a massacre. No prisoners.
We thought the world
might forgive us
for the sins of the Eldian
Empire if we wiped you out.
They'd recognize us
as good Eldians
who saved them from
the island devils.
And now, my mom and dad,
and everyone back in Liberio.
I'm gonna lose them all
because of what I did.
I'm sorry.
[ALL gasp]
[GABI]
I understand I have no right
to ask anything of any of you,
but we can't save our families
without your help.
So please.
Please don't let
our homes get trampled.
I'm begging you!
Help us, please.
We have to stop
the rumbling together!
We're begging you!
[GABI]
[FALCO]
We're begging you!
[GABI]
[FALCO]
We're begging you!
[JEAN]
Let go.
[CONNY]
Where are you going, Jean?
[HANGE] Hey! Wait, I just
poured you a fresh bowl!
It didn't work.
We couldn't convince him.
Gabi.
[LEVI]
Please shut up.
[JEAN]
Wake up.
We need to get moving.
Wait, you're really
gonna help us?
Of course. Let's go.
[JEAN] Get your mopey ass
up already, Reiner!
Your stupid face
fixed itself hours ago!
[JEAN] Gabi. I'm sorry
about kicking you.
You okay?
I'm tougher than I
might look. It's fine.
I'm glad.
[JEAN] Reiner. You're not
getting an apology.
Yeah, well. I'm good with that.
How about me?
Here comes the Cart.
[MAGATH]
Stop. There's a problem.
It's the harbor.
The Jaegerists beat us there.
They've captured it.
They must have gotten one of
the trains up and running.
There are tons of
soldiers posted
all over the port in
full anti-Titan gear.
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR] To save the world,
they must stop Eren.
With their doubts vanquished,
only their former allies
stand in their way.
Next episode: "Traitor."